NIRAJ DILIP CHAVAN

Web/UI Developer

LINKEDIN:

https://in.linkedin.com/in/niraj-chavan-8267bb98

PORTFOLIO:

https://niraj-chavan.herokuapp.com/

PROFILE

UI Developer with 7+ years of experience in designing, developing, and managing complex e-commerce sites. An energetic and imaginative young Web Developer who is able to work alongside other talented IT professionals in creating websites to the very highest standards. Skilled in developing and achieving technical objectives and goals to support the organization vision while managing & developing projects of web application.

CONTACT

PHONE: +91 96071 95436 / +91 87932 39176

EMAIL: nirajd327@gmail.com

ADDRESS: 7th Heaven, B-404, B Wing, Sr. No. 6, Hissa No. 3, D. N. Parande Park, Dhanori, Pune

- 411015, Maharashtra, India

KEY SKILLS

HTML5, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap 4/5, JavaScript, ¡Query, Typescript, Angular, ReactJS, Node JS, GraphQL, JSON, SVN, GIT, MongoDB, Jira, Rally, Microsoft Azure, Webpack, Karma

PERSONAL DETAILS

DATE OF BIRTH: 07/08/1992 **MARITAL STATUS:** Unmarried

NATIONALITY: Indian

LANGUAGES KNOWN: English, Hindi, Marathi

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (COMPUTER ENGINEERING)

Dr. D. Y. Patil Institute of Engineering & Technology, Pune University August 2011 - July 2014 Grade (%): 63.89

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Y. B. Patil Polytechnic, Pune (Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education) July 2008 - July 2011 Grade (%): 83.03

SECONDRY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE

Sharada Vidyamandir, Maharashtra Board June 2007 - July 2008 Grade (%): 86.46

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI DEVELOPER

Schlumberger, Pune, India

23/09/2019 - Present

Help to integrate Wijmo in angular component with engineering team. Build reusable libraries and code for future use. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability. Reviewing requirements and design to build new UI features.

SENIOR UI ENGINEER

Xpanxion International Pvt. Ltd. (BlueConch Technologies), Pune. India

31/01/2017 - 20/09/2019

Implementation of angular custom reusable components, JWT token implementation, performance optimization and API integration.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Connect 91 Web Solutions Pvt. Ltd. (Polyscripts Infotech Pvt. Ltd.), Pune, India

14/12/2015 - 30/01/2017

UI enhancement designs for better user experience, convert PSD into HTML and make the websites compatible with all browsers.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

WhiteCode IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Pune, India

03/07/2014 - 11/12/2015

Responsible for participating in the full life cycle of new website development and maintaining best practice procedures in all areas of work.

PROJECTS

PROJECT NAME - FIELD LOGISTIC MODULE Role and Responsibility -

Participate in all aspects of product development, from requirement analysis to product release. To analyze and debug the application to find a solution for incidents. Design and develop user interface using angular best practices. To integrate Wijmo Flexgrid components into FLM application. Optimize performance of the application. Responsible for ownership of the application code base which includes maintaining the integrity of the code, defining/enforcing standards and best practices, performing and participating in code reviews.

Team Size - 10 Role - UI Developer

Skills - Angular 7, HTML, SCSS, Wijmo Flexgrid, MongoDB, MS Azure, JavaScript, ECMAScript, Typescript, Flux Architecture, Git

PROJECT NAME - ECOM SHOPPING APPLICATION Role and Responsibility -

An online website for e-Commerce shopping build on React JS, Express JS, Node JS and mongo DB. Creating website layout/user interfaces by using HTML/CSS technologies with responsive and flexible UI. Build back-end flow and architecture. Writing code using best practices. Build admin panel for multiple roles with sets of permissions. Build architectural design of product. Design, develop and deploy modules of product. Apply deep understanding of JavaScript and React JS to build reusable UI components in a multidevice, modern web UI framework

Team Size -2

Role - UI Developer

Skills - React JS, Node JS, Mongo DB, Express JS, Git, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Heroku

PROJECT NAME - K7 SECURITY

Role and Responsibility -

To build dashboard for end customers to manage multiple devices from online website account. Develop software solutions using industry best practices and in the area of security and performance in a web and architecture environment. Collaborates with team and business owners in the design and analysis phases as part of self-organizing feature teams. Maintain source-code repository, participate in Code Reviews, and conduct design reviews. Participate in deployment of code into production.

Team Size - 8

Role - UI Developer

Skills - Angular 7, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap, JHipster, JavaScript, Typescript, Git, Rally

PROJECT NAME - SCOPERETAIL

Role and Responsibility -

Design and developed UI Interface with optimized solution for E-commerce retail product. To create custom angular 5 components for Internal framework. To create UI mock-ups, wire frames and responsive design using HTML 5, Bootstrap 4 and JavaScript. Best solutions for performance optimization techniques and unit testing strategy. Build deployment strategy and micro web-based service architecture. Integrated web rest API with front end application. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability.

Team Size - 22

Role - UI Developer

Skills - Angular 7, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, Typescript, Git, Jira, Jasmine, Karma

PROJECT NAME - CERTASLIM

Role and Responsibility -

Design and develop high performance web applications using Front-end technologies. Use mark-up languages like HTML to create user-friendly web pages. Develop new user-facing features. Build reusable code and libraries for future use. Create quality mockups and prototypes. Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability. Work closely with juniors and provide strong code reviews and feedback. Continually evaluate emerging frameworks and technologies to identify opportunities, trends and best practices that strengthen the development team.

Team Size - 6

Role - UI Developer

Skills - Angular, HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 3, jQuery, JavaScript, Git, Zoho